What... was that?
Kawachi
No. I was just getting up.
Yeah.
Is that so?
I got it.
Don't worry about it.
I'll talk to them about it on Monday.
Yeah.
Bye.
Last night, my grandfather on my mom's side passed away.
That dream... was it Grandpa and... Mom?
He didn't seem to have much of a relationship with his relatives.
My first time back in a long while, and it's for a funeral...
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
I'm here.
Ah, Daikichi? You're early.
You can put your luggage in your grandfather's bedroom.
All right.
By the way, there was a little girl out in the garden.
Did Haruko's daughter always look like that?
That's not Reina-chan.
Then whose kid is she?
Really... It's so hard to work in this kitchen.
I wonder what we're going to do now...
He was 79, so he lived a pretty full life.
That girl is apparently your grandfather's illegitimate child.
Huh?! Grandpa's child?!
He didn't tell me anything about it.
His mistress disappeared too.
Mistress? He was 79!
My, it's as embarrassing as it is pathetic.
So then, wouldn't she be your little sister?
That also means she's my aunt.
Enough! This is nothing to joke about!
You're thirty now! Don't make such insensitive remarks!
You've lived a full life, Grandpa.
How much should I spend?
However much you wish. It's up to you.
But, surely you must have an estimate?
However much you like is fine, really.
Well, these days a lot of people have a sutra read and a posthumous Buddhist name given.
She said 400 to 500 thousand.
That's quite a sum.
Hello. It's been quite a while.
Oh, Daikichi. Long time no see.
Have you been busy?
Yeah, somewhat.
Busy, busy...
Your mother has been wanting to see you.
You don't even come back for New Year's.
Here.
Wait, Reina!
Hold on! Reina!
Haruko.
Ah, Dai-chan. Long time, no see.
Mama!
Reina!
There, got you!
Be a good girl and sit still.
I don't want to!
What is it?
Nothing.
You're just so similar to your grandfather.
Daikichi, did you hear?
Yeah, Mom told me earlier.
Is it really true?
I thought my brother would get lonely, living by himself.
It seems they found her baby book.
Her name is Rin.
At any rate, to do something like this at age 79...
In any case, your father seems to have managed it somehow...
Rather, I feel like he did a good job.
Daikichi, could you get the cushions out of the closet?
What's up?
Hey, hey!
Do you want to trade with me?
No!
Give it to me like it is.
I did it!
Hey, look, look!
Reina, don't run!
My, well done!
Isn't it pretty?
It is! Reina-chan, you're really good at making a cat's cradle.
Can you do a four-step ladder next?
Here, here, Reina-chan. Let me show you.
Poop bomb!
Hey! Reina!
Uncle. Hey, Uncle.
You should get some sleep.
I'll watch over the incense.
Oh, right.
Hey, don't sleep in here!
Let's go rest out there.
What about the incense?
Daikichi said he'll watch it.
Here, up you go!
Brother, I leave it to you.
You should go sleep over there, too.
I'm fine.
Your face is a mess.
Kaga
Souichi
September 2
Heisei 23 (2011)
Yasushi Morinaga
Lay Buddhist Memorial Tablet
Now, everybody, please say your final farewells.
Reina, come here.
Okay!
This is a farewell gift for your grandfather.
Okay.
A field of flowers!
Stop it!
No! I'm making a flower garden! I wanna!
You should go say goodbye, too.
Put this on Grandpa.
Hey!
Bellflowers?
Grandpa loved those flowers.
Grandpa, these flowers will make you the happiest, won't they?
He won't... wake up anymore?
Yeah. He's not waking up.
You really are Grandpa's kid.
September 2
Heisei 23 (2011)
Yasushi Morinaga
Lay Buddhist Memorial Tablet
Maternity Book
Heisei 16 (2004)
November 22
Kaga Souichi
Yoshii Masako
Rin
Where did this Yoshii Masako go?
Someone who would leave her child behind...
Who knows what would happen even if we found her?
Good grief. How irresponsible.
My brother's become stubborn about it, too.
Be careful!
That girl, she can't talk!
She's a pain. She hasn't even lost any teeth yet!
She can talk! She's not a pain!
She can't talk! That's why Reina is so bored!
Here! You can have them all, now go away.
It's like a candy shop!
Sorry, Dai-chan!
What we need to worry about now is, who's going to look after that girl?
I can't do it. I have to run my shop.
If only she was a more proper child...
She seems slow when it comes to using words, too.
Mom, since you are staying at home, couldn't you look after her for a while?
O-Of course not! I don't have that kind of free time!
Besides, do you know how difficult it is to raise a child?!
Do you know how much I've had to sacrifice up until now?
If she was raised half-heartedly, I'd feel bad for her.
Wasn't this conversation supposed to be about who will take care of Rin?
Besides, Brother, you don't plan to do anything on your own, right?
You have to take a look at reality.
At any rate, we don't even know if she's really your grandfather's child or not.
Look, you have no idea, so you can't deny it, right?
For the time being, why don't we just look for an institution that will take her in?
What are you doing?
Rin!
Want to come home with me?
Hold on! Daikichi!
Brother!
Grandpa. I'm hungry.
Grandp—?!
Don't call me Grandpa!
After all, you're my aunt!
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
Is it good?
Yep.
Seconds?
There aren't any more side dishes.
I can make it into a rice ball.
There are no ingredients for rice balls.
Salt!
Salt?
Hey, it's still hot!
Come on, look—
But, it'll have a gentle taste.
Here, Grandpa!
I mean, Daikichi!
Daikichi sounds weird, too...
It's good.